Chapter 1: After Return, Before Return

Immediately after returning from the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica, Rio made his way to his mansion with Liselotte and Aria. They proceeded to the dining room, where King Francois was coincidentally visiting at the same time.

As soon as they had all taken their seats, Francois looked at Rio. “I believed you could do it...and you truly did. Well done bringing Liselotte back. Thank you for your efforts, Haruto.”

Rio gave a short nod and bowed his head. “It was nothing.”

“Welcome back, Liselotte,” Francois said, turning to her next. “I’m glad to see you safe.”

“I’ve caused so much trouble for the country and everyone here... Please accept my deepest apologies.”

“Don’t let it bother you. Think of it as encountering an unlucky misfortune. The Saint’s existence itself was a disaster...” Francois said, sighing at the memory of meeting Saint Erica. “I’ve asked someone to summon Cedric and Julianne, as well as Princess Christina and Princess Flora, who are close to you. They will arrive shortly, so show them that you’re safe.”

“Thank you for your consideration.”

“Of course. The main discussion will start after they arrive, but I’m sure Haruto must be very confused right now. Did you hear about what happened to the mansion on your way here?” Francois asked, glancing at Gouki and Kayoko.

“No, I was told it would be better to wait for everyone to be present.”

That was what Charlotte had said to him on the way here. She had spoken teasingly, but it was indeed the more efficient option.

“I see...” Francois hesitated, but made up his mind quickly after. “In short, invaders attacked the castle shortly after you left.”

“Wha—?!” Rio and Liselotte both widened their eyes.

Francois paused, thinking about how to explain things in a way that wouldn’t cause them excess concern. The assailants were deeply related to Rio’s fated enemy, so he chose his words carefully.

“Rest assured. Although the scale of the attack was large, the matter was resolved with relatively little harm. It was all thanks to the efforts of this mansion’s residents. I visited today in order to express my gratitude over the incident.”

“Is that so...”

Rio and Liselotte looked a little less anxious, but there was still too little information to dispel their confusion.

“Excuse me. Princess Christina, Princess Flora, as well as Duke Cretia and his wife have arrived.” A female knight announced the arrival of the invited guests.

“Thank you for the invitation.”

The first to enter after the knight were the foreign royals, Christina and Flora, but they promptly moved aside after giving their short greetings. They were probably being considerate of Liselotte’s parents, Duke Cedric Cretia and Duchess Julianne Cretia.

“Your Majesty...”

As her parents, they wanted to call out to their daughter immediately, but as a duke’s family, they couldn’t do such a thing. With his position as a noble in mind, Cedric greeted King Francois first. That being said, his gaze and attention were completely focused on his kidnapped daughter who had safely returned.

“There’s no need to greet me. I will not stand in the way of a father-daughter reunion,” Francois said, dismissing the need for any noble etiquette.

“Thank you for your consideration. Oh, Liselotte!” After a quick bow, Cedric rushed straight over to his daughter. His wife Julianne was right behind him.

“Thank goodness you’re safe...” she sighed, sweeping Liselotte, who had stood up to meet them, into a loving hug with Cedric.

“Mother, father...” Liselotte was unable to budge from their embrace. There were tears in her eyes and her voice was trembling. Everyone else in the room watched over the family quietly.

After some time, Cedric and Julianne turned to Rio and bowed their heads deeply.

“Sir Amakawa... No, Haruto. Thank you for bringing my daughter back.”

“I acted of my own accord, so don’t worry about it,” Rio said, shaking his head.

“Oh my...”

Those words must have resonated in Julianne’s heart, as she looked at her daughter with a sigh of admiration. Liselotte tried to feign composure, but her cheeks were tinted a shy pink.

“Thank you, truly...” Cedric smiled softly and shook Rio’s hand, emphasizing his gratitude from the bottom of his heart.

“You’re welcome. However, it might be a bit too early to celebrate. I have some bad news to report as well...” Rio said, looking at Francois.

“I expected as much. I also need to explain what happened over here to you. But let’s start with your report first.”

Thus, Rio and Francois explained to each other what they had experienced during Rio’s absence.

◇ ◇ ◇

Two days ago, on the outskirts of the Holy Democratic Republic of Erica...

The sun was just about to set behind the stone house set up in the woods.

“Mm...” Rio, who had been wounded in his battle with Saint Erica, opened his eyes.

Where...

The familiar ceiling of the stone house greeted him. He tried to recall what had happened with his still-groggy mind.

“Sir Haruto...?”

A familiar voice called to him from beside his bed, so he turned to look that way. Liselotte was seated in a chair next to his bed, having nursed him while he was unconscious. Their gazes met.

“Liselotte...?”

“Umm, how are you feeling? If it hurts anywhere...”

Her hands hovered over his body, prepared to cast Cura to heal him.

“I’m fine. Nothing hurts.”

Rio slowly sat up, moving his arms to check the condition of his body. He could feel his body was stiff from sleeping, but he wasn’t in any pain.

“Thank goodness...!” Liselotte exhaled in relief, slumping over as all her strength left her. Her hovering hands settled on clinging to Rio’s right arm on the bed, squeezing his hand tightly.

“...” The sudden contact to his hand almost made Rio flinch, but he stifled his body’s reflexes with a gulp of air.

“Thank goodness... Truly...”

Liselotte was crying. Her head was hanging downwards, but both her slender body and lovely voice were trembling.

“Sorry, I must have made you worry,” Rio apologized quietly.

“No, I should be the one to apologize! I’ve caused you so much trouble...”

Liselotte had lifted her face to argue back, but was looking down once again with the latter half of her words. Rio watched her like he was unsure of what to say.

“It was no trouble at all.” He quickly gave her a gentle smile of assurance. Then, he moved his left hand and squeezed her hands softly between his.

“Sir Haruto?” Liselotte asked, looking up in confusion.

“I’m here of my own will. Being bedridden after charging in so triumphantly is pathetic of me, but I’ve never thought of it as a trouble caused by you.” Rio spoke slowly, as though he were explaining things to a crying child.

“You’re not pathetic at all.” Liselotte’s voice cracked as she spoke. She still looked like she was blaming herself.

“That’s a relief to hear. I’m so glad you were unharmed. We both came out of this benefiting from something, so please don’t look so upset,” Rio said, the sharp outlines of his face easing in joy.

With that, Liselotte was unable to argue any further. Her body flinched a little in surprise.

“Okay...” she murmured with a small nod.

The two of them gazed at each other at close range, holding each other’s hands.

“W-Wait, help! How do I get back down?!” she shrieked, panicking.

She’s forgotten how she flew by herself, huh? How ridiculous...

She was failing to control her ability consciously because she had obtained the ability without learning any of the necessary basics. There were times where she had no control at all and just activated her abilities at maximum power. This was something she had in common with Hiroaki. Rio continued to watch her for a while, until...

“H-Haruto!”

It seemed that flying consciously was just too hard for her. Rio sheathed his sword and began to fly towards her. He slowed down just before crashing into her, gently catching her in both his arms.

“...”

Satsuki opened her eyes fearfully.

“Good work today,” Rio’s smiling face said to her.

“R-Right... Thanks.”

Satsuki blushed, stammering her gratitude.

“Let’s go back to the ground. I’ll give you my review then.”

Thus, the two of them descended.

◇ ◇ ◇

A short distance away from the pavilion where Charlotte was observing from...

“Aww, man... I couldn’t land a single hit.” Satsuki hung her head in disappointment.

“There were holes in your plan, but it was a good plan overall. I liked how you broke up the terrain to use as projectiles. You started flying by yourself to attack me, but I guess you didn’t notice that part.”

“Y-Yeah... I was so immersed in fighting...”

So she had been flying unconsciously after all.

“Activating your abilities consciously will be your next goal.”

“Flying by myself is so much scarier than being carried while flying. I’m shocked.”

“A major hurdle to the spirit art of flying is overcoming the fear of heights. Your emotions have a large influence on your abilities.”

Spirit arts brought about phenomena by conveying the imagination of the spirit art user into the mana in the atmosphere. If the caster feared falling, then the activation of the art would also become unstable.

“At the end of the battle, all I could think about was how scared I was of falling.”

“That’s normal, and you need to know the feeling of fear. Otherwise you may hurt yourself flying while your control is still lacking.”

What was most important was to remain calm and unaffected by those emotions.

“I see...”

“You know that you have the foundations for flying. Work hard from here.”

“Yup! Oh, that’s right. There’s one other ability I want to be able to use.”

“What is it?”

“You know how there are times when you move as though you teleported?”

“...Like this?”

Rio demonstrated the move that came to mind. He distanced himself from Satsuki and immediately moved back beside her.

“Y-Yes! That! How do you do that?” Satsuki asked excitedly. To her, it truly appeared as though he teleported.

“You know how you used wind to accelerate yourself mid-battle?”

“Yeah. I’m able to do that by imitating you. I wanted to move fast like you...”

“If you can do that, then you’ve got the foundation for it as well. It’s a technique that’s necessary in flying spirit arts as well.”

“Hmm...”

“However, it’s harder and more dangerous to do that flying. You’ll need another ability besides the spirit arts...”

And so it was difficult to learn overnight, Rio explained.

“What kind of ability?”

“Hmm... You know how I told you about extraneous movements in combat?”

“Ah, right. Something about how when the opponent braces their weapon, you can read their next move by using that.”

“Right. This is related to that, but have you heard of a telegraphed punch?”

“A punch...that you communicate?” Satsuki asked in confusion. It seemed she had no idea.

“If someone suddenly swung their fist before you, you’d think they’re about to hit you, right?” Rio held his fist up in a swinging pose.

“Yeah, I’d be shocked. So that’s an extraneous movement.”

“Yes. This pose tells your opponent you’re about to punch them, which is why it’s called a telegraphed punch.”

There were no telegraph systems in this world, which is why this was a method of explanation he could only use with Satsuki.

“I see.”

“Aside from that, things like kicking, swinging your weapon, or running are actions that people unconsciously recognize as tells.”

Rio assumed each one of the poses he mentioned.

“Yeah. I can easily tell which pose is what. Removing these kinds of movements is the purpose of martial arts forms, right?”

“Yes. You might have realized this already, but I remove all of those kinds of movements when I accelerate. That’s why it gives the illusion of teleportation.”

By moving from a complete stop, relying on only the spirit art to move, and refraining from making any other action, he could move as though a section of a video had been skipped entirely.

“I think I get the logic. You’re basically running without making a running pose, right? And at an extremely rapid speed.”

“It’s more like flying than running, but yes. This technique is especially effective against opponents facing you—if you look from the side, it’s clear I’m moving without running,” Rio said, then flew to a spot a short distance away. This time, instead of moving forwards to Satsuki, he passed by her.

“Umm, you’re so fast I can’t follow you with my eyes... How many kilometers per hour are you even going?” Satsuki complained with a grimace. She couldn’t even tell whether he was flying or running.

“Let’s see. I change speeds depending on my distance to my opponent, so it isn’t consistent, but... Even at my fastest speed, I cannot surpass the speed of sound.”

“Th-The speed of sound?! Oh, but less than that... Still, that’s amazing.”

The speed of sound was 340 meters per second. Converted to kilometers per hour, it was a little under 1,200.

“I’ve surpassed it once before, but doing so creates a phenomenon known as a sonic boom. It’s a great burden on the body, and there’s a limit to how much relief the arts can provide.”

That’s why he normally set his own limit to a subsonic speed. For the record, he normally flew at a slower speed when traveling—an average speed of 100 kilometers per hour.

“S-So you can surpass it if you want to... Well, no wonder it looks like you’re teleporting.”

Even at a subsonic speed, he could cross a hundred meters in a single instant. He could approach his opponent in the blink of an eye.

“That’s why it’s dangerous. The movement takes a single instant, so you have to control everything from activating the art to stopping it in that instant. If you’re inexperienced at casting, you’ll risk colliding with your opponent and other obstacles. It’s also difficult to change your trajectory while accelerating. If you don’t choose your timing properly, you might self-destruct.”

“And I have to think about how to attack after moving...”

“Yes. The ideal situation is to attack the moment you finish moving.”

“That isn’t a human technique, is it?” Satsuki eyed Rio in suspicion.

“It is a very difficult technique. That’s why you should first focus on using spirit arts to fly.”

“Okay! Oh, by the way...”

“Yes?”

“Do you have a name for it?”

“A name...for what?”

“For your high-speed movement.”

“No, not particularly...”

None of the spirit arts Rio used had any particular move name. There were some casters that found it easier to imagine their techniques by giving them a name, but Rio had never felt the necessity.

“Instant movement, or instamove for short. Or maybe accelamove, short for accelerated movement. Or maybe even shukuchi, like the ancient martial arts?”

“Shukuchi isn’t a martial art, but a fable from ancient mythology...”

“Spirit arts are plenty similar to ancient mythology.”

“I suppose...”

He personally disagreed, but he wasn’t able to explain why, so he didn’t say so out loud.

“They’re the same in the sense that they’re both fantasy techniques. So, regarding your high-speed movement: how about Shukuchi? I believe the origin of the word comes from the ground shrinking underneath your feet. Yup, it fits you perfectly.”

“Well, I don’t mind either way... You seem to care a lot about the move name, though.”

“Because it’s pitiful for such an amazing move to not have a name!”

“I’m honored you think that way.” Rio smiled happily.

“Right...” At Rio’s joyous face, Satsuki looked to the side shyly.

“Then let’s go back for now. I’d like to give a lecture on spirit arts and check out your Divine Arms a little more.”

Thus, Rio and Satsuki headed back to the pavilion.

◇ ◇ ◇

And so, they moved on to investigating Satsuki’s Divine Arms. What they wanted to know was whether something like the beast of the land was sleeping within her weapon as well.

Seated in a circle under the pavilion were Rio, Satsuki, Aishia, Alma, and Charlotte.

In the past, Rio and Alma had done a simple investigation of Satsuki’s Divine Arms in private. However, they only knew that the spear was special, and nothing else. It was a completely out-of-place artifact, and they had no way of studying what sorcery was in it, or how it was made.

They didn’t know about the beast of the land back then, so they hadn’t considered the possibility of something similar to a spirit sleeping within the weapon. Besides, multiple heroes had materialized their Divine Arms in front of Aishia before, but she had never sensed the presence of a spirit from them.

But they were yet to conduct an investigation under the assumption that something was sleeping within. And so...

“Okay, can you lend your Divine Arms to Aishia?”

“Sure. Here you go, Aishia.”

They decided to have Aishia, the spirit, take it in her hands and investigate it herself. This was the same action that Dryas had done on Rio the first time he had visited the spiritfolk village with Aishia sleeping within him.

At any rate, if there was something like the beast of the land sleeping within the spear, it would be dangerous to trigger it carelessly. The chances of something terrible happening were low, but investigating in an unpopulated place like this was for the best.

“...” Aishia stared at the spear she accepted from Satsuki in silence.

“How’s it look, Aishia?”

“I can’t feel any spirit presence when it’s materialized as a weapon. But there’s definitely a connection between the spear and Satsuki. I could tell as soon as I touched it.”

“Huh, so that’s how it is...” Satsuki looked between the weapon and her hands. Naturally, she couldn’t see anything with the naked eye.

“Is it like the path between a contract spirit and us?” Alma asked Aishia.

“Yeah, it’s similar to that.”

“Is it impossible for there to be a spirit in the weapon, Alma?” Rio asked Alma. As a dwarf, she had more profound knowledge when it came to spirits and weapons.

“There are some spirits who choose an object to represent them instead of a contract. Like a spirit that resides in a tree, for example.”

The spirit who resided in a tree was probably Dryas. Since Charlotte was present, she purposefully avoided saying her name.

“However, spirits prefer to reside along leylines—places where the land is abundant with magic essence. I’ve never heard of one choosing to dwell in a weapon. If it were something like a spirit stone, then I could understand, but...”

Satsuki’s Divine Arms had no spirit stones embedded as decorations.

“I don’t know what a spirit stone is, but the item that summoned the heroes is an ancient artifact called a sacred stone. Is it possible for a spirit to reside in that instead?” Charlotte asked.

“That is another possibility. But the sacred stone disappeared when Satsuki was summoned, right?”

“Yes. Father believes the stone became the Divine Arms.”

“If the sacred stones are spirit stones, is it possible for a spirit to reside within them and transform into a weapon?” Rio asked, seeking Alma’s opinion once again.

“As far as I know, such a technique doesn’t exist... But it doesn’t look like time-space sorcery is being used when the weapons are materialized. It looks similar to the phenomena of spirits materializing...”

“I had the same thought. In this case, instead of there being a spirit inside the sacred stone or Divine Arms, it’s more like the Divine Arms itself is a spirit?”

“If that’s true, then the Divine Arms would have two forms: a weapon form and a beast form... Three if you include the sacred stone form.”

“Can spirits have multiple forms?”

Alma shook her head slowly. “Not to my knowledge...”

“Whether the Divine Arms is holding a spirit or is a spirit itself, I can’t feel any presence in its current form,” Aishia chimed in.

“I see. In that case, the beast of the land might not be part of the Saint’s Divine Arms...”

Alma groaned in thought. The more they investigated, the more possibilities emerged. There was no way of reaching a conclusion.

“The connection between Satsuki and the Divine Arms... I’ll try following that link to see if I can probe further.”

Aishia suddenly stood up with Satsuki’s spear in hand. She proceeded to walk out of the pavilion, followed by Rio and the others.

“Are you examining the Divine Arms right now?”

Sara, Miharu, Celia, and Latifa, who were training separately, came up to them. Kayoko and Louise’s knights also came over to watch.

“It might be dangerous, so everyone should stand back,” Aishia said, distancing herself.

“Everyone stand behind me just in case.” Rio stood in front of the group to be ready to protect them.

“It’s a little scary...” Satsuki was trembling faintly. An unknown beast could be residing within her Divine Arms, so it was only natural.

“We’re just examining it, so I don’t think anything will happen. This is just in case,” Rio said reassuringly.

Meanwhile, Aishia began her examination. With the spear in both hands, she closed her eyes, following the connection between the weapon and Satsuki to dive within. Thus, she reached the visualization of the world within the Divine Arms—

I can’t see anything...

It was pure white. It was as though there was a thick fog covering everything, preventing her from seeing more than a few centimeters to the front.

If she hadn’t followed the path between Satsuki and the weapon, she wouldn’t have been able to dive within here. She had barely been able to do so by relying on that connection.

There’s a wall.

When she followed it farther, she bumped into a barrier. It wasn’t visible to the eye, as her vision was filled with nothing but white. Just what was on the other side of the barrier? Aishia tried to push her way through.

Just then, the wall was stained with something black. The darkness crossed the wall and attempted to cover Aishia as well.

“Huh?!” Aishia immediately withdrew from the Divine Arms, snapping her eyes open. She stared down at the spear in her hands, bewildered.

What...?

The darkness that crossed the wall had been trying to tell her something before she broke away.

I...

Was there something she was meant to be doing? Was there something she had forgotten? She didn’t know why, but that was the feeling flooding into her right now.

“What’s wrong, Aishia?!” Rio noticed the abnormality and came running over immediately.

“I’m fine...” she replied, swaying on her feet. However, her face was extremely pale. She was even whiter than she usually was.

“Ai-chan!”

Worried about Aishia’s state, Miharu came running over soon after to support her body.

“Did you see something?” Rio asked nervously.

“I couldn’t see anything,” Aishia muttered. “It was pure white, then pitch black, but...”

She looked at Rio’s face, followed by Miharu’s. She felt like there was something she had to tell them, but the words wouldn’t come out. She looked unusually anxious.

“All right... Let’s stop here for today.”

Seeing her in such a state, Rio decided to stop the investigation on the Divine Arms.

“Pesky things...” Erica clicked her tongue in slight annoyance. Then, she started walking forward while still releasing her destructive light.

“Gah, it’s no good. At this rate...” He wouldn’t be able to protect everyone. But he absolutely didn’t want that. Rio desperately resisted the force pushing against him, maintaining the barrier.

“...” Aishia watched Rio’s profile, her heart feeling like it would burst from her chest.

“Give it up, Dragon King. That is the limit of a human vessel. My vessel is also a human, but her body ceased to be human the moment she became a hero. She is far different from you,” Erica said to Rio.

“Huh...?” Satsuki looked perplexed. As a hero, it was a sentence she couldn’t overlook. If what Erica just said was true, heroes were no longer humans. Did that mean she wasn’t human either?

Just then, a slash of intense light came falling down.

“Durandal!” Latifa came rushing over, carrying Celia. She must have been preparing her magic while everyone was fighting. The range had been adjusted a lot compared to the fight with the Hero Killer Draugul, but the strongest attack magic in Celia’s arsenal struck Erica directly.

The surprise attack from behind caught Erica with her guard down, successfully dealing more damage than any other attack until now. The half of Erica’s body that touched the slash was completely disintegrated. As a result, the attack Erica was using against Rio’s essence barrier also vanished.

“To think a human could use transcendent magic... Did that woman teach you?” The disintegrated half of Erica’s body rapidly restored itself. She looked away from Miharu to glare at Celia for a brief moment.

“No way...” Celia was dumbfounded. Erica swung her arm at Celia and Latifa in annoyance. However...

“I won’t let you!” Rio flew in between them, taking the blow from her arm in their stead. Of course, his physical body was enhanced.

“Gah!” A terrible cracking sound could be heard from the right arm and ribcage that Rio used to guard them.

“Rio!” Latifa screamed in fear.

“I’ll be fine! You stay back. No—you should all flee!” Rio shouted, tackling Erica back two meters.

“How annoying... I see. So this is the strength of humans. Each of you may be insignificant alone, but you can support each other by flocking together. I was able to surface today through a stroke of luck, but it seems I’m out of time... Very well. Let’s see if you can protect yourselves to the end,” Erica said with a sigh, then vanished.

“Did she leave...?” Satsuki murmured. But that wasn’t possible; Rio immediately looked at the tsunami of magic essence rising on the other side of the plains.

“Wha...” He fell speechless. It wasn’t an amount of essence that could be handled by a human—or any other living creature in this world, for that matter. Even if someone could hold this much essence in their body, there had to be a reasonable limit for any living creature, and this amount clearly surpassed that. It surpassed it by so much, he didn’t know what to do.

“No...!” Rio yelled hoarsely. “She hasn’t merely departed! She changed locations so that no one would get in her way! Get the airship away right...!”

Right now, was what he wanted to say, but where would they go?

There was so much magic essence, it was impossible to imagine what would happen. The range of its effect could be unfathomable. There was no way the airship could flee high enough in time.

It was impossible for all of them to run. He could only save a few of them at most. He’d have to make a choice on who to save.

“...”

Rio didn’t know what to say.

“Haruto...” Just then, Aishia stood next to Rio.

“Aishia...”

“I’m sorry...” she apologized.

“What for...?”

She suddenly started speaking. “I remembered... Not everything, but the reason why I don’t have memories. And what my role is...”

“What are you saying...?” Everything that had happened today was so bewildering.

Aishia continued. “I was an empty shell. A temporary container to store power. That’s why I was meant to return that power to you with an explanation.”

“Is this the time for that, Aishia?” In this situation that resembled the end of the world.

“But because of you, Haruto, I stopped being an empty shell.”

It was almost as if...

“You gave me my name. A precious name, warm like the spring.”

Almost as if she was saying goodbye...?

“I was so happy,” Aishia said earnestly. “Thank you.” She touched Rio on the cheek, thanking him as though it was the end.

“I know I should return this power to you. But...” It was at this moment that Aishia looked a little hesitant.

“But I can’t do it,” she said, shaking her head.

“Why not...?”

“You already have everyone,” Aishia said, looking around at everyone. They were all watching her anxiously.

“The lonely child named Rio grew up into you, Haruto. I cannot steal your precious bonds with everyone.”

Aishia stared at everyone’s faces closely. She then turned around to face the wave of essence across the plains with a look of determination. “The only person you need to forget is me. That’s why...”

Rio couldn’t comprehend what she was saying at all. No, he didn’t want to.

“This is our final farewell. I will defeat the Saint—no, that man—myself...” Aishia left. But just before she flew off, she glanced back at Rio.

“Bye-bye, Haruto.”

She smiled gently and chuckled cutely. She wasn’t her usually emotionally detached self, but a young woman with a vivid range of emotions.

Thus, Aishia left Rio’s side.

Epilogue: The Transcendent Ones

“No!” Rio yelled desperately, ignoring the pain in his cracked ribs and arm.

“Aishia!”

He called for Aishia frantically; he had a bad feeling about this.

If Aishia left here... He had a feeling something very, very bad would happen.

Horrified, he used his wind spirit arts to accelerate after her.

“You said it yourself!” he yelled. “You said we’d always be together!”

Because he had everyone else? What was she saying?

“Everyone...”

That’s right, everyone...

“Everyone includes you, Aishia!” Rio roared.

He reached for Aishia, who was already far ahead.

“So don’t go alone!”

As though extending his hand towards the unreachable sky...

“AISHIA!” Rio called her name.

◇ ◇ ◇

Erica stood far in the distance. Aishia released her power—the power that didn’t originally belong to her.

I don’t want Haruto to be lonely anymore. That’s why I’ll...!

She would be his substitute. Aishia was trying to use that power with determination in order to remove the towering threat before them, protecting Rio and Haruto’s precious bonds...

“Why are you trying to use the Dragon King’s power, you creepy little puppet? Did you deceive him and steal it? Just like how you did to me.”

Erica glared at Aishia, enraged. The mountain of magic essence flowing from Erica responded to her fury, swelling in size.

Thus, the power of the two sides increased more and more.

Haruto...?

Aishia whipped around in a panic. She could tell the power she had released was being drawn in towards its original owner—Rio.

“No! Don’t come near me!” she screamed in a fluster. She desperately fought against Rio’s pulling power, resisting the draw.

“So that’s what it is, Dragon King.” Erica’s eyes were locked on the power flowing between Rio and Aishia. She seemed to comprehend something from that.

“You...” She glared at Rio. “You betrayed me too!”

Her rage had reached its peak. She yielded the last of the rationality she had been maintaining in the little time she had left. Immediately after, a tsunami of dirt rose from the ground, reversing the heavens and earth.

Or so it seemed.

◇ ◇ ◇

It wasn’t a sight that was of this world.

The ground shook—the world shook.

“What...is that...?” The Galarc Kingdom army beside the lake looked up in horror.

The shape was similar to the beast of the land. However, the beast of the land couldn’t compare to this. It would have looked tiny in comparison. The creature was enormous in size.

There was no doubt this creature was the cause of the earthquake. It was undeniably a symbol of catastrophe.

“WROOOOOOH!”

With eyes that had lost all rationality, it roared up at the skies. This time, the earth flipped over.

“Wha...!” Everyone standing on the bank of the lake was frozen in fear.

A volcano erupted, sending debris flying.

No, calling it that wasn’t enough. The earth had flipped over, literally. A tsunami of dirt tall enough to swallow everything spread before them, advancing towards the lake.

“So this is the power of a hero...” Galarc King Francois mumbled, as though he had given up on everything. The legends of the heroes were no exaggeration after all. No, the legends seemed trivial in the face of this. At the very least, there were no records of monsters like this in the legends.

“What are the heroes? No, that no longer matters...”

There was no need to question it anymore since they were dead anyway. There was no way for mankind to survive such an enormous natural disaster.

In a dozen or so seconds, Francois and everyone else would be swallowed along with the lake. Even the bravest soldier was no more than a mere human—there was no way for them to defy nature. The soldiers of the Galarc Kingdom army all had expressions of resignation at their imminent deaths. There were some like Duke Gregory among them, who were wailing shamefully, unable to accept that.

“It’s not over yet!” Celia yelled.

“That’s right!” Latifa yelled too.

“The two of them haven’t given up yet!”

“We can’t give up either!”

“Let’s all put up a barrier together!”

Sara, Alma, and Orphia also yelled frantically, encouraging themselves.

“Use my essence! Take all of it!”

“Everyone gather together, quickly!”

“Let me help out too!”

Miharu, Satsuki, and Liselotte also yelled.

“...” Seeing the girls’ faith in Rio and Aishia under such a situation rendered Francois speechless. No matter how strong the magic essence barrier was, there was a limit to the area it could cover. There was no way it could withstand the overwhelming mass of the flying debris. Their greatest hope, Rio, was helpless before Erica earlier. Yet the girls were still optimistic.

“We’ll have to entrust this to them, Father. Our fate is in the hands of Sir Haruto and Lady Aishia. If they fall, then we’ll graciously fall with them,” Charlotte said to Francois, giggling as she looked around at the girls that were working hard. That seemed to strengthen Francois’s resolve, as...

“All forces that can create essence barriers, prepare for impact!”

He gave the order to resist death.

◇ ◇ ◇

The earth flipped over, and the end of the world approached.

“Why did you come, Haruto?” Aishia stood facing Rio, who had arrived belatedly.

“I don’t want to lose anyone important to me anymore. That includes you, Aishia. I want to be with everyone.”

Perhaps it was greedy of him. Perhaps he sounded like a spoiled child. Even so, he didn’t want to lose his most important bonds.

That was why Rio expressed his feelings with determination.

“But you can’t stay with everyone anymore, Haruto. You’ll lose everyone precious to you. You should have just let me go. I could have become your substitute...”

Now it was too late. Aishia was nothing more than the safekeeper—she could no longer use the power. Sensing that, Aishia had an extremely flustered and saddened expression on her face. She hung her head in deep regret.

Rio began to speak about himself. “I was always afraid of losing the people important to me... No, I’m still afraid now. That’s why I tried to distance myself from them. But...”

He continued.

“You’re the one who taught me that was unnecessary. Aishia, you saved me from solitude. That’s why...”

He faced himself as a person.

“That’s why there’s no way I’ll leave you alone. I won’t let you go alone if I know you’re not coming back.” Rio grabbed Aishia by the shoulder, staring straight into her face as he made his point.

“Haruto...” Tears flowed from Aishia’s eyes.

Rio wiped them away. “It’s fine. You said I can’t be together with everyone anymore. I don’t know what you mean by that, but it’s fine. This is my decision.” He smiled at Aishia gently.

“No matter what happens, I won’t regret anything.”

Rio looked away from Aishia, turning his back to the lake where the people precious to him waited. He faced the looming despair approaching them.

The overwhelming mass covered the entire sky. If they continued standing here, they would be swallowed in a matter of seconds.

“That’s why...!”

Rio released his power.

He still had no idea what this power was, but for some strange reason, he understood how to use it.

Oddly enough, it felt familiar in his hands.

Why was that?

Make a sword.

Rio imagined the power as a sword.

This was the easiest way for him to use this power right now.

His instinctual understanding told him that.

Aishia came to stand beside him.

“That power is too much for a human body to handle... If you force yourself to use it, your body will fall apart. But that’s why I’m here,” she said, gently touching Rio’s hand that was holding the sword. As soon as she did so, she disappeared as though she had turned into her spirit form. But immediately afterwards...

“...”

Rio gasped, his eyes widening.

He could tell the power was flowing from his body.

No, he could tell his body was being rebuilt.

In order to make the power easier to use, his existence was ascending to something beyond that of a human.

Now it’ll be fine. Go on, Haruto, Aishia’s voice echoed.

“Haaah!”

Rio slashed his sword horizontally with all his might. A blinding light that could erase everything was released from his blade. “Wha...” Those standing beside the lake were speechless. The tsunami of dirt that was tall enough to cover the skies had been swallowed by a blinding light.

And when that blinding light eventually faded, the tsunami of dirt had vanished without a trace.

◇ ◇ ◇

Immediately after, Saint Erica stood where the enormous creature had towered before. There had been nearly a kilometer of distance between them before, but Rio had closed that gap in an instant...

“Ghh...”

...and embedded his sword in Erica’s heart.

“Heh... Hehe...”

Erica was smiling. The voice coming from her mouth wasn’t the man’s, but the original Erica’s.

“I’m sorry. I had no other choice,” Rio said to Erica. This time, he would kill her. He was able to actually kill her in his current state.

“You’re so kind. There’s no need to apologize,” Erica mumbled with a vacant look in her eyes. “Even if you didn’t deal the final blow, I would have died anyway. I can tell. I used more power than I can handle. The price of that is death. But thanks to you, I can die. I’m so, so happy—I’m overjoyed. I’ve always, always wanted to die... So thank you for killing me.” Erica smiled from the bottom of her heart.

“You...” Rio was at a loss for words.

You never wanted to do this in the first place, did you?

“Humans are extremely foolish and ugly creatures. That’s why I don’t regret what I’ve done. I still think those fools should die. But there are kind people out there. Foolishly kind people. You must be one of them. So I have a favor to ask of you, kind one. Whether you listen is up to you,” Erica said eloquently, even as the light in her eyes dimmed. She really didn’t seem to have long left. Rio realized that.

“What is it?”

“There’s a remote village in the nation that I established, fifty kilometers east of the capital. The worst village with the worst people living in it. But deep in the mountains past the village, there’s a waterfall, where his grave is... If possible... I’d like to be...”

Erica’s consciousness was beginning to fade. Honestly speaking, her explanation was rather insufficient, but...